Finding aid for the Karl G. Yoneda papers, 1892-1998, bulk 1925-1989 LSC.1592
UCLA Library Special Collections
- 10. Political Subject Files, 1892-1995 bulk 1945-1995
  - 10.2 Political Activities and Subjects, 1905-1995, bulk 1962-1995
    - Hawaii Pono Journal, 1970-1971 (Box 42, Folder 1)
      Three issues of: Hawaii Pono Journal. Honolulu: Hawaii Pono Journal, 1970-1971.
    - Hibakusha: Surviving Victims of the Atomic Bombings of Hiroshima and Nagasaki, 1972-1995 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Hiroshima and Nagasaki Atomic Bombings, 1970-1995 (Box 42, Folder 3)
      Also Includes Yoneda's draft of his speech, "No More Hiroshima and Nagasaki," delivered at Benjamin Franklin JR High School, San Francisco, California, on August 8, 1970.
    - International Hotel, 1976-1978 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - ?????????? Jakku Shirai Kenkyu Kaiho, 1986 (Box 42, Folder 5)
      ?????????? Jakku Shirai Kenkyu Kaiho. Hakodate-shi: Jakku Shirai Kenkyukai. No. 1 (Jan., 1983)-no.2 (Sept., 1983); and "Spanish Vets Banquet Sanka Sihryoshu" published in March, 1986.
    - Japanese American Activism and Journalism, 1984-1986 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Japanese and Japanese American Community: Japanese Immigrant Labors in the U.S., 1905-1907 (Box 42, Folder 7)
      Negative photostat prints of news clippings from "S.F. Chronicle" published between 1905 and 1907.
    - Japanese and Japanese American community: Japanese Cultural & Community Center of Northern California (JCCCNC), 1980-1987 (Box 42, Folder 8)
      Five issues of: JCCCNC Update. San Francisco: Japanese Cultural & Community Center of Northern California, 1985-1987.
    - Japanese and Japanese American Community: Kimochi, Inc., 1971-1988 (Box 42, Folder 9)
      Also includes programs coordinated by Kimochi, Inc.
    - Japanese and Japanese American Community: Little Tokyo, 1974-1991 (Box 42, Folder 10)
      Contains materials on the development of Little Tokyo.
    - Japanese and Japanese American Community: Nihonmachi Leagal Outreach, 1983-1985 (Box 42, Folder 11)
      Nihonmachi Leagal Outreach Newsletter. San Francisco: Nihonmachi Leagal Outreach. V. 2, no. 1-2, and v. 3, no. 2. Also includes a brochure and pamphlet.
    - Japanese and Japanese American Community: San Francisco Japantown Struggles, 1974-1986 (Box 42, Folder 12)
      Includes materials by Committee against Nihonmachi Eviction (CANE) and about the Japanese Salvation Army building.
    - Japanese and Japanese American Community: Workers Strikes, 1966-1987 (Box 42, Folder 13)
      Disputes and strikes against employers, Miyako Hotel, New Otani Hotel, Kiku Restaurant, Restaurant Horikawa, Benihana, Nippon Club, Di Giorgio Farm, Tanita Farm, Japan Food Corporation (JFC), Hinode Tofu Company, Nishimoto Trading Company, etc.
    - Japanese and Japanese American Community: Miscellaneous, 1965-2000 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Japanese American Library = ????????·??? Nikkei Kenkyu Senta Toshokan, 1986 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Japanese American Farm Workers, 1970-1979 (Box 43, Folder 3)
      Includes materials on Japanese agricultural workers and the Nisei Farmers League.
    - Japanese American Publications, 1970-1985, undated (Box 43, Folder 4)
      News clippings and some issues of newspapers and newsletters published by Japanese American organizations. Includes Cane Newsletter; LTPRO News; Little Tokyo News; New Dawn; Toyo-do; Taishu; Pacific Citizen; Nikkei; Nikkei Sentinel; Haguruma; Japanese Newcomers Services Nobirukai; Japanese American Democratic Club; San Francisco Center for Japanese American Studies; the JAM Newsletter; JWRO Kaiho; and JAHSSC.
    - Japanese Communist Party: 50th Anniversary, 1972 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Japanese Communist Party: Elections, 1971-1990 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Japanese Communist Party: Publications, 1979 October-1989 November (Box 43, Folder 7)
      Five issues of: Bulletin, Information for Abroad. Nihon Kyosanto Chuo Iinkai. Tokyo: Central Committee, Communist Party of Japan; two issues of: Japan Labour News: Toitsu-Rosokon. Tokyo: Toitsu-Rosokon; four issues of: Japan Press: Weekly Bulletin. Tokyo: Japan Press Service; two issues of: Japan Press News: Nihon Kyosanto. Tokyo: Japan Press Service; and six issues of: Japan Press Weekly: News and Comments. Tokyo: Japan Press Service.
    - Japanese Communist Party: Miscellaneous, 1932-1990 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Japanese Emperor, Emperor Hirohito, 1945-1997 (Box 44, Folder 2)
      Includes disputes about the Japanese emperor's US visit.
    - Japanese Labor Party, 1977-1979 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Japanese Political Issues (1 of 2), 1971-1979 (Box 44, Folder 4)
      Includes issues on Japanese Red Army, radicals, and the Narita International Airport incident.
    - Japanese Political Issues (2 of 2), 1972-1995 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Japanese School Textbook, 1939 (Box 44, Folder 6)
      Contains a school textbook for moral training published in 1939: ??? Monbusho. ???????. ?5?. Jinjo Shogaku Shushinsho. Dai 5-kan. Tokyo: Nihon Shoseki, 1939.
    - Japanese Women, 1920 (Box 44, Folder 7)
      News clippings from a journal, "The Ladies' Home Journal" published in January 1920.
    - Japan-US Relation and Social Issues, 1965-1991 (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Ludlow Massacre in 1914, 1949 and 1964 (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - May Day Parades, 1933 and 1939 (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - Mixed Marriages, 1938-1939, 1967-1986 (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - National Alliance against Racist and Political Repression, 1973-1989 (Box 44, Folder 12)
      Includes six issues of: The Organizer: Newsletter of the National Alliance against Racist and Political Repression. New York: Alliance, 1973-1989.
    - Nichi-Bei Times Workers' Association and 1975 Nichi-Bei Workers Strike, 1974-1975 (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - ?????? Nihon Imin Gakkai, 1985-1991 (Box 44, Folder 14)
      Includes ??????? Imin Kenkyukai Kaiho. [Tokyo]: Imin Kenkyukai.
    - Nuclear Disarmament, 1978-1987, bulk 1982 (Box 44, Folder 15)
    - Oxnard Sugar Beet Workers' Strike in 1903, 1965-1980 (Box 44, Folder 16)
      Also includes correspondence from Rinjiro Sodei.
    - Racism: Anti-Asian, 1972-1985 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Racism: Anti-Apartheid, and Others, 1965-1987 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Revolutionary Communist Youth Brigade, 1980 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - San Francisco State College Strike and S. I. Hayakawa, 1968-1975 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Service Employees International Union, Local 87, 1983-1985 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - ??????? Shin Nihon Funjin no Kai = New Japan Women's Association, 1986-1999 (Box 45, Folder 6)
      Five issues of: ??????? Shin Fujin Shinbun. Tokyo: Shin Nihon Fujin no Kai, 1986-1999.
    - Socialist Women, 1907 (Box 45, Folder 7)
      Photocopies of articles from: The Socialist Woman. Chicago: The Socialist Woman. V. 1, no. 4 (Sept., 1907).
    - Southwest Labor Studies Association Conferences, 1978-1984 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Southwest Labor Studies Association Conferences, 1985-1995 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Southwest Labor Studies Association Publications, 1976, 1981 (Box 46, Folder 3)
      Two issues of: Southwest Economy & Society. Albuquerque: [s.n.].
    - Trade Union Movement in Japan, 1981-1987 (Box 46, Folder 4)
      Also includes "Brief Labor Picture in Japan: Based on 1980 Figures" compiled by Yoneda.
    - U.S. Peace Council: Martha Acevedo' Club Assignment, 1989-1990 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Vietnam War, 1965-1979 (Box 46, Folder 6)
      Includes photographs of the Anti-Vietnam War march, San Francisco, California, on April 15, 1967, and Yoneda and his grandchildren attending the Anti-Vietnam War rally, San Francisco, California, on April 27, 1968.
    - Wendy Yoshimura Fair Trial Committee, 1975-1980 (Box 46, Folder 7)
      Includes correspondence between Wendy Yoshimura and Elaine Yoneda.
    - Wholesale Produce Market Workers Union, 1936-1937 (Box 46, Folder 8)
      All items are available only in photocopied format.
    - World Conference against A and H Bombs, 1958-1993 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - World Congress for Peace, 1973 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - World Youth Festival, 1984-1985 (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous Materials, 1940-1946, 1966-1994 (Box 46, Folder 12)
      Fliers, news clippings, a pamphlet, and other materials regarding various activities.
    - Asian and Asian American Community: Asian Population in the U.S., 1982-1991 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Japanese Labor Party, 1977-1979 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Nuclear Disarmament, 1978-1987, bulk 1982 (Box 49, Folder 7)